<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Venues on Computational Humanities Research 2025</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Venues on Computational Humanities Research 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/venue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accomodation in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/accomodation-in-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/accomodation-in-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Aarhus offers a range of excellent hotels – from well-known international ones to unique accommodations. Get an overview of the hotels here.&#xA;We recommend that participants book their stay at one of the hotels listed below. Networking with fellow researchers is a key aspect of any conference, and this year&amp;rsquo;s event is designed to foster meaningful connections. By providing a range of accommodation options and encouraging attendees to stay at the same hotels, we hope to create more opportunities for interaction outside of formal sessions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Dinner at Restaurant Havnær</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/conference-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/conference-dinner/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Restaurant Havnær Join us for the conference dinner on December 5th at Restaurant Havnær, a name that translates to &amp;ldquo;close to the ocean&amp;rdquo; in Danish. Nestled at the edge of Aarhus Ø, this beautiful venue offers breathtaking views over Aarhus Bay, creating the perfect setting for a memorable evening.&#xA;At Havnær, the focus is on authentic experiences, combining exquisite gastronomy with warm, informal hospitality. Their approach reflects the charm of Jutland, meeting guests at eye level and offering a relaxed atmosphere where you can simply sit back, enjoy the moment, and take in the stunning surroundings from the SHIP building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Delights in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/culinary-delights-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/culinary-delights-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Aarhus boasts a vibrant and diverse dining scene, offering something for every palate. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a gourmet aficionado or simply in search of a satisfying meal, the city has plenty to explore. For a casual start, head to the Latin Quarter or Jægergårdsgade, where you&amp;rsquo;ll find a wide range of dining options.&#xA;Fine Dining For those seeking fine dining, Aarhus is home to several Michelin-starred restaurants, which you can explore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Conference Venue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/finding-the-venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/finding-the-venue/</guid>
      <description>The main address of the CHR2024 conference is Bartholins Allé 8, 8000 Aarhus C, where the registration and breakfast take place on the first day. For other details on transportation, see also Getting Around in Aarhus and Conference Dinner Transport.&#xA;Map of the Venue At CHR2024, all locations are conveniently set within a short walking distance. See the overview below:&#xA;A Building 1321 Registration and Breakfast on Wednesday (December 4, 2024)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting around in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/getting-around-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/getting-around-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Discover the many travel options that Aarhus has, and read more about how to buy tickets for public transport in Aarhus.&#xA;For a venue map, visit Finding the Venue. Details on CHR&amp;rsquo;s guided transport to the conference dinner are available at Conference Dinner Transport.&#xA;Travel Options Walking The entire city is clean, compact and well-organised, which makes walking an excellent and enjoyable way to get around. To walk from the centre of the city to the university takes approximately 40 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sightseeing in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/sights-in-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/sights-in-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Experience Aarhus before and after the CHR2024 Conference&#xA;Aarhus, Denmark’s second-largest city and affectionately known as “The City of Smiles,” offers a delightful mix of modern attractions and historic charm. Whether you arrive early or extend your stay after the conference, there’s plenty to discover. To help you plan, we have curated some recommendations for must-see experiences in and around Aarhus.&#xA;Activities ARoS Art Museum As a participant in the upcoming CHR2024 conference, you have a unique opportunity to explore the renowned ARoS Art Museum, where art truly comes to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travelling to Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/travelling-to-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/travelling-to-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>There is a wide range of travel options for you to arrive to Aarhus - just as you would like:&#xA;By Air Travelling to/from:&#xA;Aarhus Airport Aarhus Airport (Tirstrup) is located 40 km north of the city and offers direct international flights to a number of European destinations, for instance Oslo, Stockholm, Gothenburg, Manchester, London (Stansted and Gatwick), Berlin, Munich, Nice, Rome and Cyprus. Please visit their website for information on flight arrival/departure times.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
