<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CHR 2025 on Computational Humanities Research 2025</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CHR 2025 on Computational Humanities Research 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/</guid>
      <description> APPLY FOR THE BOARD! Looking to make an impact in Computational Humanities? The Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) is recruiting an Early Career Representative and a Proceedings Officer to join its board. These volunteer roles are perfect opportunities to shape the field and support its growing community. Apply by 21 February 2025! ... Read More </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code of conduct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>Purpose of the Code of Conduct The organisers of the Computational Humanities Research conference are committed to providing a safe and inclusive space, with respectful and equitable treatment for everyone. This code is meant to guide speakers, session chairs, organisers, attendees, and people who might be involved with the conference in other ways. It was inspired by the code of conduct of the BRIDGES 2022 conference published in bridges2022.com/code-of-conduct.&#xA;Approach and principles This code draws on an intersectional perspective, considering the interlocking character of various dimensions such as gender, sexuality, race/ethnicity, class, age, disability, and religion/creed as axes of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover ARoS Art Museum with Free Voucher</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/aros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/aros/</guid>
      <description>As a participant in the upcoming CHR2024 conference, you have a unique opportunity to explore the renowned ARoS Art Museum, where art truly comes to life. We are excited to offer all attendees vouchers that can be used during your stay in Aarhus, giving you the chance to experience the museum’s extraordinary collections and exhibitions. Using Your Vouchers Your vouchers are valid from Saturday, November 30, 2024, through Sunday, December 8, 2024.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Lauren Klein</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/lauren-klein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/lauren-klein/</guid>
      <description>About Lauren We are happy to announce that Lauren Klein, Winship Distinguished Research Professor and Associate Professor in the departments of Quantitative Theory &amp; Methods and English at Emory University, will give a keynote speech at the Computational Humanities Research 2024 Conference. Lauren Klein also directs the Digital Humanities Lab at Emory University, and before moving to Emory, she taught in the School of Literature, Media, and Communication at Georgia Tech.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Leon Derczynski</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/leon-derczynski/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/leon-derczynski/</guid>
      <description>About Leon We are happy to announce that Professor Leon Derczynski, principal research scientist in LLM Security at NVIDIA and prof in Natural Language Processing (NLP) at ITU Copenhagen (IT University of Copenhagen) will give a keynote speech at the Computational Humanities Research 2024 Conference in Aarhus, Denmark.&#xA;Professor Derczynski contributes to leading bodies on LLM securing, being on the OWASP LLM Top 10 core team, working on ML Commons, and founder of the ACL SIG on NLP Security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Past Events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archive/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 CHR2024 was a three-day conference held on December 4 to 6, 2024. The program committee and organizers accepted 49 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3834/. See https://2024.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2024.&#xA;CHR2023 CHR2023 was a three-day conference held on December 6 to 8, 2023. The program committee and organizers accepted 49 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3558/. See https://2023.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2023.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/community/</guid>
      <description>We cordially invite you and other interested parties to join the Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description>Community Please join our Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!&#xA;Contact For questions, ideas, or support, contact the organizers or drop us a line on the forum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description> The Computational Humanities Research (CHR) community is an international and interdisciplinary community that supports researchers with an interest in computational approaches to the humanities. Learn more about the people behind CHR2025 and the organisation of CHR:&#xA;People → Board → Journal → Community → Archive → </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accomodation in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/accomodation-in-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/accomodation-in-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Aarhus offers a range of excellent hotels – from well-known international ones to unique accommodations. Get an overview of the hotels here.&#xA;We recommend that participants book their stay at one of the hotels listed below. Networking with fellow researchers is a key aspect of any conference, and this year&amp;rsquo;s event is designed to foster meaningful connections. By providing a range of accommodation options and encouraging attendees to stay at the same hotels, we hope to create more opportunities for interaction outside of formal sessions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR 2025 in Luxembourg</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/chr2025-in-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/chr2025-in-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>The 6th edition of the Computational Humanities Research (CHR) conference will take place at the Luxembourg Centre for Contemporary and Digital History (C²DH) at the University of Luxembourg from 9 to 12 December 2025. Renowned for its focus on providing a dedicated venue for presenting computational work that bridges formal methods and traditional inquiry in the arts and humanities, the CHR conference offers a platform to explore computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches, alongside theoretical reflections on these methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR Journal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/</guid>
      <description>The Cambridge University Press journal Computational Humanities Research (CHR) is the official journal of the CHR Conference. CHR is an open access journal in the computational humanities, publishing transdisciplinary papers that are grounded in humanities research questions and use computational, quantitative methodologies to analyse humanities data in its various forms.&#xA;CHR publishes research that tackles big questions and solves problems pertaining to the humanities through advanced computational methods, contributing empirically to major theoretical, cultural, and historical inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR2024 Best Paper Awards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/best-paper-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/best-paper-awards/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 showcased outstanding work, highlighting cutting-edge computational approaches to humanities research. A heartfelt thank you to everyone who participated, whether by presenting your work or contributing to meaningful discussions at the conference.&#xA;We are delighted to reveal the winners of the Best Long Paper and Best Short Paper Awards. With so many exceptional submissions, we are pleased to also give honourable mentions to the two runners-up in each category.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Dinner at Restaurant Havnær</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/conference-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/conference-dinner/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Restaurant Havnær Join us for the conference dinner on December 5th at Restaurant Havnær, a name that translates to &amp;ldquo;close to the ocean&amp;rdquo; in Danish. Nestled at the edge of Aarhus Ø, this beautiful venue offers breathtaking views over Aarhus Bay, creating the perfect setting for a memorable evening.&#xA;At Havnær, the focus is on authentic experiences, combining exquisite gastronomy with warm, informal hospitality. Their approach reflects the charm of Jutland, meeting guests at eye level and offering a relaxed atmosphere where you can simply sit back, enjoy the moment, and take in the stunning surroundings from the SHIP building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Delights in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/culinary-delights-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/culinary-delights-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Aarhus boasts a vibrant and diverse dining scene, offering something for every palate. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a gourmet aficionado or simply in search of a satisfying meal, the city has plenty to explore. For a casual start, head to the Latin Quarter or Jægergårdsgade, where you&amp;rsquo;ll find a wide range of dining options.&#xA;Fine Dining For those seeking fine dining, Aarhus is home to several Michelin-starred restaurants, which you can explore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity and Inclusion at CHR2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>New initiatives, like the Anti-Discrimination Committee and reduced fees, reinforce the CHR2024 Conference’s commitment to accessibility and inclusivity, ensuring all participants feel valued and supported. Since its inception five years ago, the Computational Humanities Research (CHR) Conference has developed into a prominent and well-regarded event, attracting researchers who apply computational methods across various humanities fields. This growth has enriched the CHR community, diversifying both the range of topics explored and the contributors involved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Conference Venue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/finding-the-venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/finding-the-venue/</guid>
      <description>The main address of the CHR2024 conference is Bartholins Allé 8, 8000 Aarhus C, where the registration and breakfast take place on the first day. For other details on transportation, see also Getting Around in Aarhus and Conference Dinner Transport.&#xA;Map of the Venue At CHR2024, all locations are conveniently set within a short walking distance. See the overview below:&#xA;A Building 1321 Registration and Breakfast on Wednesday (December 4, 2024)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting around in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/getting-around-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/getting-around-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Discover the many travel options that Aarhus has, and read more about how to buy tickets for public transport in Aarhus.&#xA;For a venue map, visit Finding the Venue. Details on CHR&amp;rsquo;s guided transport to the conference dinner are available at Conference Dinner Transport.&#xA;Travel Options Walking The entire city is clean, compact and well-organised, which makes walking an excellent and enjoyable way to get around. To walk from the centre of the city to the university takes approximately 40 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/people/</guid>
      <description>Programme Chairs &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; Local Organizers &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; Programme Committee </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sightseeing in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/sights-in-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/sights-in-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Experience Aarhus before and after the CHR2024 Conference&#xA;Aarhus, Denmark’s second-largest city and affectionately known as “The City of Smiles,” offers a delightful mix of modern attractions and historic charm. Whether you arrive early or extend your stay after the conference, there’s plenty to discover. To help you plan, we have curated some recommendations for must-see experiences in and around Aarhus.&#xA;Activities ARoS Art Museum As a participant in the upcoming CHR2024 conference, you have a unique opportunity to explore the renowned ARoS Art Museum, where art truly comes to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Board</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/board/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 served as the decor for the launch of the Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR). We have established a comprehensive board structure with dedicated officers:&#xA;Melvin Wevers (President) Folgert Karsdorp (Vice-President) Alie Lassche (Social Media &amp; Event Officer) Barbara McGillivray (Diversity and Inclusion Officer) Kristoffer Nielbo (Journal Liaison) Together with our robust diversity and inclusion guidelines, this structure ensures our community remains open, welcoming, and representative of all its members.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travelling to Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/venue/travelling-to-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/venue/travelling-to-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>There is a wide range of travel options for you to arrive to Aarhus - just as you would like:&#xA;By Air Travelling to/from:&#xA;Aarhus Airport Aarhus Airport (Tirstrup) is located 40 km north of the city and offers direct international flights to a number of European destinations, for instance Oslo, Stockholm, Gothenburg, Manchester, London (Stansted and Gatwick), Berlin, Munich, Nice, Rome and Cyprus. Please visit their website for information on flight arrival/departure times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancies in the CHR Board</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/announcements/board-vacancies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/announcements/board-vacancies/</guid>
      <description>Looking to make an impact in Computational Humanities? The Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) is recruiting an Early Career Representative and a Proceedings Officer to join its board. These volunteer roles are perfect opportunities to shape the field and support its growing community.&#xA;Apply by 21 February 2025! Vacancy 1: Early Career Representative for the Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) The Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) is seeking an Early Career Representative to join its board.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
