<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CHR 2025 on Computational Humanities Research 2025</title>
    <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CHR 2025 on Computational Humanities Research 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conference Proceedings are Published</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/proceedings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/proceedings/</guid>
      <description>The CHR2025 conference proceedings are now online, comprising 97 papers and adding up to almost 1,600 pages. It is also the first time that the proceedings of a CHR conference are published at a new venue. After having published the proceedings of the first five editions of CHR at CEUR Workshop Proceedings, we are very happy to announce that CHR has found a new publication venue in the recently launched Anthology of Computers and the Humanities (ACH).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Paper Awards for Early Career Researchers</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/ecr-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/ecr-awards/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce that there will be two Best Paper Awards for early career researchers at CHR2025!&#xA;Thanks to the generous support of Digital Scholar, CHR2025 will feature one Best Paper Award in each paper category — long and short papers. Each award includes a prize of 250 € and is reserved for papers whose main author or authors are early career researchers.&#xA;We look forward to recognizing innovative work by emerging voices in computational humanities!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 11:11:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/cfp/</guid>
      <description>In the arts and humanities, the use of computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches has considerably increased in recent years. This research is characterized by the use of formal methods and the construction of explicit, computational models. This includes quantitative, statistical approaches, but also more generally computational methods for processing and analyzing data, as well as theoretical reflections on these approaches. Despite the undeniable growth of this research area, many scholars still struggle to find suitable research-oriented venues to present and publish computational work that does not lose sight of traditional modes of inquiry in the arts and humanities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code of conduct</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>Purpose of the Code of Conduct The organisers of the Computational Humanities Research conference are committed to providing a safe and inclusive space, with respectful and equitable treatment for everyone. This code is meant to guide speakers, session chairs, organisers, attendees, and people who might be involved with the conference in other ways. It was inspired by the code of conduct of the BRIDGES 2022 conference published in bridges2022.com/code-of-conduct.&#xA;Approach and principles This code draws on an intersectional perspective, considering the interlocking character of various dimensions such as gender, sexuality, race/ethnicity, class, age, disability, and religion/creed as axes of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover ARoS Art Museum with Free Voucher</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/aros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/aros/</guid>
      <description>As a participant in the upcoming CHR2024 conference, you have a unique opportunity to explore the renowned ARoS Art Museum, where art truly comes to life. We are excited to offer all attendees vouchers that can be used during your stay in Aarhus, giving you the chance to experience the museum’s extraordinary collections and exhibitions. Using Your Vouchers Your vouchers are valid from Saturday, November 30, 2024, through Sunday, December 8, 2024.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Els Lefever</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/els-lefever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/els-lefever/</guid>
      <description>About Els Lefever Els Lefever is Associate Professor at the LT3 language and translation technology team at Ghent University, which conducts fundamental and applied research for NLP. She started her career as a computational linguist at the R&amp;D-department of Lernout &amp; Hauspie Speech products and holds a PhD in computer science from Ghent University on ParaSense: Parallel Corpora for Word Sense Disambiguation (2012). Els has a strong expertise in machine learning of natural language and multilingual natural language processing, with a special interest for computational semantics, language modeling of lower-resourced languages and multilingual terminology extraction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Miguel Escobar Varela</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/escobar-varela/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/escobar-varela/</guid>
      <description>About Miguel Escobar Varela Miguel Escobar Varela is Associate Professor of Theatre Studies at the National University of Singapore and deputy director of the Centre for Computational Social Science and Humanities (CSSH). He studies the changing landscape of Southeast Asian cultural heritage by combining fieldwork with computational methods (such as NLP, computer vision and network analysis). His aim is to understand how the production and reception of cultural forms have changed over time, in areas such as the performing arts, print media, and digital spaces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/</guid>
      <description>Conference Proceedings are Published The CHR2025 conference proceedings are now online, comprising 97 papers and adding up to almost 1,600 pages. It is also the first time that ... Read More Best Paper Awards for Early Career Researchers at the CHR2025 conference! We are happy to announce that there will be two Best Paper Awards for early career researchers at CHR2025! ... Read More Call for Bids CHR2026 The board of the Computational Humanities Society hereby invites proposals to host the annual CHR conference in December 2026.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Past Events</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/archive/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 CHR2024 was a three-day conference held on December 4 to 6, 2024. The program committee and organizers accepted 49 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3834/. See https://2024.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2024.&#xA;CHR2023 CHR2023 was a three-day conference held on December 6 to 8, 2023. The program committee and organizers accepted 49 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3558/. See https://2023.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2023.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/community/</guid>
      <description>We cordially invite you and other interested parties to join the Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Community Please join our Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!&#xA;Contact For questions, ideas, or support, contact the organizers or drop us a line on the forum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/about/</guid>
      <description> The Computational Humanities Research (CHR) community is an international and interdisciplinary community that supports researchers with an interest in computational approaches to the humanities. Learn more about the people behind CHR2025 and the organisation of CHR:&#xA;People → Board → Journal → Community → Archive → </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accommodation</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/accommodation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/accommodation/</guid>
      <description>⚠️ Warning: Phishing alert: We have been alerted to fraudulent messages asking CHR25 attendees for travel dates and accommodation details. Please be vigilant and do not trust or reply to any messages about your accommodation from unknown contacts. There are several options for accommodation during your stay in Luxembourg.&#xA;Two hotels are located directly on the University’s Belval Campus: Ibis Esch Belval and Residhome Luxembourg Esch-Belval. Conveniently located near the conferene venur, they are also close to the train station and bus stops, allowing you to have easy access to Luxembourg&amp;rsquo;s other renowned destinations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR 2025 in Luxembourg</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/chr2025-in-luxembourg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/chr2025-in-luxembourg/</guid>
      <description>The 6th edition of the Computational Humanities Research (CHR) conference will take place at the Luxembourg Centre for Contemporary and Digital History (C²DH) at the University of Luxembourg from 9 to 12 December 2025. Renowned for its focus on providing a dedicated venue for presenting computational work that bridges formal methods and traditional inquiry in the arts and humanities, the CHR conference offers a platform to explore computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches, alongside theoretical reflections on these methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR Journal</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/journal/</guid>
      <description>The Cambridge University Press journal Computational Humanities Research (CHR) is the official journal of the CHR Conference. CHR is an open access journal in the computational humanities, publishing transdisciplinary papers that are grounded in humanities research questions and use computational, quantitative methodologies to analyse humanities data in its various forms.&#xA;CHR publishes research that tackles big questions and solves problems pertaining to the humanities through advanced computational methods, contributing empirically to major theoretical, cultural, and historical inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR2024 Best Paper Awards</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/best-paper-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/best-paper-awards/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 showcased outstanding work, highlighting cutting-edge computational approaches to humanities research. A heartfelt thank you to everyone who participated, whether by presenting your work or contributing to meaningful discussions at the conference.&#xA;We are delighted to reveal the winners of the Best Long Paper and Best Short Paper Awards. With so many exceptional submissions, we are pleased to also give honourable mentions to the two runners-up in each category.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR2025 Programme</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/programme/</guid>
      <description>Programme for the pre-conference workshops on Tuesday, 9th December 2025, and the main conference days on Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday, 10th-12th December 2025.&#xA;All accepted papers can be found in the proceedings, published in the Anthology of Computers and the Humanities.&#xA;If you are presenters, please consult the instructions here.&#xA;The main venue of CHR2025 is the Maison du Savoir (MSA), University of Luxembourg, Belval Campus, 2 place de l’Université, L-4365 Esch-sur-Alzette, Luxembourg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR2025 Review Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/reviewer-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/reviewer-instructions/</guid>
      <description>If you notice any problems meeting the review deadline or with your assignments, or if you have any questions about EasyChair, please contact us as soon as possible.&#xA;Please note that we assign a small number of community member and non-expert reviews in order to promote interdisciplinarity, diversity, and community engagement.&#xA;Scope of Submissions CHR accepts papers without considering their perceived significance. This means we welcome:&#xA;Papers with negative or inconclusive results Small case studies Prototypes and proofs of concept See the full Call for Papers here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Location and Venues</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/location-and-venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/location-and-venue/</guid>
      <description>The conference takes place at the University of Luxembourg, Belval Campus, 2 place de l’Université, L-4365 Esch-sur-Alzette, Luxembourg.&#xA;Belval Campus Location&#xA;Download the Belval Campus mobility map&#xA;Maison du Savoir (Auditorium) All of the conference sessions and breaks take place in the Maison du Savoir (please refer to the downloadable Belval Campus mobility map), on the 3rd floor. This building is located on the Belval Campus of the University of Luxembourg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Social Event</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/conference-social-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/conference-social-event/</guid>
      <description>Join us for the conference dinner on the 11th of December at Come à la Maison.&#xA;We look forward to sharing this special dining experience with you. Be sure to register for the CHR 2025 conference and conference social event.&#xA;Conference Dinner Transport We can take you to the conference dinner by private bus that will leave from the Ibis Hotel in Belval at 7:15 PM. The return bus will depart from the restaurant at 10:30 PM back to Belval.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity and Inclusion at CHR2024</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>New initiatives, like the Anti-Discrimination Committee and reduced fees, reinforce the CHR2024 Conference’s commitment to accessibility and inclusivity, ensuring all participants feel valued and supported. Since its inception five years ago, the Computational Humanities Research (CHR) Conference has developed into a prominent and well-regarded event, attracting researchers who apply computational methods across various humanities fields. This growth has enriched the CHR community, diversifying both the range of topics explored and the contributors involved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facilities on Belval Campus</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/belval-campus-facilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/belval-campus-facilities/</guid>
      <description>Belval Campus is the main hub of the University of Luxembourg, offering a modern and vibrant academic environment that integrates education, research, and innovation. It is located on the site of a former steelworks in Esch-sur-Alzette, symbolizing the country’s commitment to knowledge and technology.&#xA;Key features and facilities Various restaurants and bars offering Korean, Asian, Luxembourgish, Italian, and other cuisines. Belval Plaza is a mall with restaurants, shops, a drugstore, and a cinema.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Catering</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/green-catering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/green-catering/</guid>
      <description>Choosing green catering for a conference reflects a commitment to sustainability and environmental responsibility. Thus, we have collaborated with our partner Dussmann to provide a selection of locally sourced, organic, and seasonal food options. All the food is prepared within a 30km radius of Belval. A huge effort has also been made on waste management by simply avoiding any packaging and single-use dishware.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of what is on offer:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Speakers</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/keynote-speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/keynote-speakers/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce the keynote speakers of the CHR2025 conference!&#xA;Miguel Escobar Varela is Associate Professor of Theatre Studies at the National University of Singapore and deputy director of the Centre for Computational Social Science and Humanities (CSSH). He studies the changing landscape of Southeast Asian cultural heritage by combining fieldwork with computational methods (such as NLP, computer vision and network analysis). His aim is to understand how the production and reception of cultural forms have changed over time, in areas such as the performing arts, print media, and digital spaces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/organization/</guid>
      <description>Programme Chairs Taylor Arnold, University of Richmond, USA Margherita Fantoli, KU Leuven, Belgium Ruben Ros, Universiteit Utrecht, The Netherlands Contact: pc[at]computational-humanities-research[dot]org&#xA;Local Organizers All local organizers are affiliated with the Luxembourg Centre for Contemporary and Digital History - C²DH, Université du Luxembourg&#xA;Sofia Papastamkou (Chair) Vanessa Napolitano (Co-chair) Sean Takats (Co-chair) Finola Finn Elisabeth Guérard Tugce Karatas Kirill Mitsurov Contact: local[at]computational-humanities-research[dot]org&#xA;Programme Committee Alberto Acerbi, University of Bristol Ali Al-Laith, Computer Science Department Pascal Amsili, Sorbonne Nouvelle Tara Andrews, University of Vienna Maria Antoniak, University of Washington Brian Ballsun-Stanton, Macquarie University David Bamman, University of California, Berkeley Jean Barré, ENS-PSL Andreas Baumann, University of Vienna Nicolas Baumard, CNRS Kaspar Beelen, School of Advanced Study, University of London Marijke Beersmans, KU Leuven Katherine Bode, Australian National University Emanuela Boros, EPFL Judith Brottrager, TU Darmstadt Manuel Burghardt, Computational Humanities, University of Leipzig Patrick Burns, University of Texas at Austin Florian Cafiero, Sciences Po Paris Jean-Baptiste Camps, École nationales des chartes Flavio Massimiliano Cecchini, KU Leuven Kent Chang, University of California, Berkeley Thibault Clérice, ALMANaCH, Inria Mariona Coll Ardanuy, Barcelona Supercomputing Center (BSC-CNS) Evelien de Graaf, KU Leuven Quinn Dombrowski, Stanford University Antoine Doucet, University of La Rochelle Anton Ehrmanntraut, Universität Würzburg Pascale Feldkamp, CHCAA Mark Finlayson, Florida International University Evelyn Gius, Technical University Darmstadt Thora Hagen, Leibniz Institute for the German Language Julian Häußler, Technische Universität Darmstadt Serge Heiden, ENS de Lyon Petra Heřmánková, Aarhus University Berenike Herrmann, Bielefeld University Tobias Hodel, Digital Humanities/Walter Benjamin Kolleg/Universität Bern Yuerong Hu, Department of Information and Library Science, Indiana University Bloomington Federica Iurescia, Università Cattolica Mia Jacobsen, Aarhus University, Center for Humanities Computing Lars Johnsen, National Libary of Norway Anne Kandler, Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology Folgert Karsdorp, Meertens Institute Vojtech Kase, Aarhus University Mike Kestemont, CLiPS Kristian Kjelmann, Aalborg University Leonard Konle, Würzburg University Marijn Koolen, Royal Netherlands Academy of Arts and Sciences - Humanities Cluster Ross Kristensen-McLachlan, Centre for Humanities Computing, Aarhus University Maciej Kurzynski, Lingnan University Sarah Lang, Zentrum für Informationsmodellierung, Centre for Digital Humanities (ZIM-ACDH), Karl-Franzens-Universität Graz Jan Langenhorst, TUD Dresden University of Technology Alie Lassche, Aarhus University Benjamin Lee, University of Washington Hoyt Long, University of Chicago Li Lucy, University of California, Berkeley Cerstin Mahlow, ZHAW Zurich University of Applied Sciences Enrique Manjavacas, Leiden University Patricia Martin-Rodilla, Spanish National Research Council Kirill Maslinsky, INALCO Barbara Mcgillivray, King&amp;rsquo;s College London David Mimno, Cornell University Ben Nagy, IJP PAN Clemens Neudecker, Berlin State Library Julia Neugarten, Radboud University, Nijmegen Andreas Niekler, Universität Leipzig Kristoffer Nielbo, Aarhus University, Center for Humanities Computing Aarhus Damien Nouvel, INaLCO Marco Passarotti, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart Federico Pennino, Bologna University Francesco Periti, Università degli Studi di Milano Statale Federico Pianzola, University of Groningen Michael Piotrowski, University of Lausanne Thierry Poibeau, LaTTiCe-CNRS Nils Reiter, Department for Digital Humanities, University of Cologne Matteo Romanello, Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne Laurent Romary, INRIA &amp;amp; HUB-ISDL Christine Roughan, Princeton University Martin Ruskov, University of Milan Yann Ryan, Leiden University Martin Schlenk, Leipzig University Christof Schoech, University of WÃ¼rzburg Marijn Schraagen, Utrecht University Stefan Schweter, Bayerische Staatsbibliothek München, Digital Library/Munich Digitization Center Artjoms Šeļa, Institute of Czech Literature, Czech Academy of Sciences Olga Seminck, Laboratoire Linguistique Formelle Wenyi Shang, University of Missouri Adela Sobotkova, Aarhus University Elena Spadini, University of Basel Rachele Sprugnoli, Università degli Studi di Parma Zachary Stine, University of Central Arkansas Laure Thompson, Princeton University Lauren Tilton, University of Richmond Mikko Tolonen, University of Helsinki Maria Mihaela Trusca, KU Leuven Andreas van Cranenburgh, University of Groningen Linde Van den Eede, KU Leuven Marieke van Erp, KNAW Humanities Cluster Nanne van Noord, University of Amsterdam Joris Van Zundert, Huygens ING - Royal Netherlands Academy of Arts and Sciences (KNAW) Caroline Vandyck, University of Antwerp Klara Venglarova, Universität Graz Stella Verkijk, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam Chahan Vidal-Gorène, École Nationale des chartes-Université PSL, Centre Jean-Mabillon, Calfa Georg Vogeler, Center of Information Modelling in the Humanities, University of Graz Melanie Walsh, University of Washington Melvin Wevers, University of Amsterdam Matthew Wilkens, Cornell University Naitian Zhou, UC Berkeley Additionally, we thank the following reviewers for their assistance with feedback to the papers:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practicalities</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/practicalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/practicalities/</guid>
      <description>Presentations and slides Please note that you can only use the main laptop (running on Wondows 11) the organizers make available in each room.&#xA;File format In person presentations: Please prepare a file of your slides in PDF or PPT format.&#xA;Distant presentations: Please prepare an audivisual recording of your presentation.&#xA;Upload Please upload your file to the cloud folder of the conference (information provided by email) by Monday 8th December.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/registration/</guid>
      <description>We are using EasyChair to handle conference registration. After logging in, select the link Registration ↣ start registration. If you are an author of a paper, please use the same login that you had for your submission. Otherwise, you can use an existing account or create a new EasyChair account for free.&#xA;Registrations will remain open until 11:59 PM on November 20, 2025, in the last time zone globally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Board</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/about/board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/about/board/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 served as the decor for the launch of the Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR). We have established a comprehensive board structure with dedicated officers:&#xA;Melvin Wevers (President) Folgert Karsdorp (Vice-President) Alie Lassche (Social Media &amp; Event Officer) Barbara McGillivray (Diversity and Inclusion Officer) Kristoffer Nielbo (Journal Liaison) Together with our robust diversity and inclusion guidelines, this structure ensures our community remains open, welcoming, and representative of all its members.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transportation</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/transportation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/transportation/</guid>
      <description>Transportation in Luxembourg (bus, train, tram) is free. You can check all the necessary information on the website of the Public Transport Administration or the website of the national railroad company CFL.&#xA;From the airport to the Belval Campus (2, place de l’Université L-4365 Esch-sur-Alzette), you have different options:&#xA;Bus and train From the airport to the Belval Campus, take bus number 29 or 223 to Luxembourg Central Station (Gare).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated Anonymity Guidelines for CHR Submissions</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/anonymity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/anonymity/</guid>
      <description>23 May, 2025&#xA;We have revised our anonymity period policy to better balance double-blind review with the need for early research visibility.&#xA;The anonymity period now runs until notification of acceptance (September 18). Authors may post preprints on repositories like arXiv, Zenodo, or HAL before submission, but should not link to these from their anonymized papers. Reviewers will focus strictly on anonymized submissions and provide feedback on how well anonymity is maintained in practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancies in the CHR Board</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/board-vacancies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/news/board-vacancies/</guid>
      <description>Looking to make an impact in Computational Humanities? The Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) is recruiting an Early Career Representative and a Proceedings Officer to join its board. These volunteer roles are perfect opportunities to shape the field and support its growing community.&#xA;Apply by 21 February 2025! Vacancy 1: Early Career Representative for the Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) The Society of Computational Humanities Research (SCHR) is seeking an Early Career Representative to join its board.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venue</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/venue/</guid>
      <description>The CHR2025 conference will take place from the 9th to the 12th of December at the Luxembourg Centre for Contemporary and Digital History (C²DH), University of Luxembourg. The conference will be held at the Belval Campus, a historic former steel industry site that has been transformed into a modern educational and economic hub.&#xA;Practical Information Quick access to practical information about CHR2025:&#xA;Discover the Venue → Getting around in Luxembourg → Conference Social Event → Belval Campus Facilities → Conference Registration → Discover Luxembourg Discover Luxembourg&amp;rsquo;s incredible sights and experience the Grand Duchy&amp;rsquo;s cuisine:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://2025.computational-humanities-research.org/workshops/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, 9 December we will be hosting three pre-conference workshops. Participation is including with the registration fee. Space is limited, so please select the workshop you are interested in during the registration process. Information about the three workshops are available below.&#xA;Impresso Datalab: Exploring and annotating multilingual digitised newspapers and radio archives Organizers: Marten Düring, Caio Mello and Vy CAO&#xA;This three-hour hackathon-style workshop offers hands-on experience with the Impresso Datalab, a platform that provides access to multilingual historical newspaper and radio archives along with machine learning models for semantic enrichment tasks like named entity recognition, OCR quality assessment, and press agency detection.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
